# Dipali Makadia

Los Angeles, CA | +1 (562) 825-8686 | dipali.makadia@gmail.com | https://dipalimakadia.github.io/Dipali-s-Portfolio/ | https://www.linkedin.com/in/dipali-makadia/

#### SUMMARY

4 years of experience in software development covering frontend, backend, and full-stack tasks, skilled in responsive web development, W3C standards, cross-browser compatibility, web accessibility, Agile and Scrum methodologies, problem-solving, troubleshooting, testing, debugging, version control, and client communication.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Programmer Analyst**

Cognizant

05/2021 - 01/2022

Collaborated on the O2 project, utilizing HTML5, CSS, SCSS, JIRA, NodeJS, ES6, JavaScript, JQuery, GIT, and Adobe Target to develop engaging and responsive front-end components.

#### **Associate Interface Developer**

Digitas

05/2019 - 05/2021

- Programmed the **DMI project** with team, using HTML5, CSS3, Highcharts, D3, GIT, Handlebars, NPM, JavaScript, ES6, jQuery, Bootstrap, NodeJS, and ReactJS to develop visually appealing, interactive graphs and front-end components.
- Built a single-page app containing a dashboard, graphs, roadmap, and calendars, conducted testing, and collaborated closely with UX team and back-end developers to maintain project quality.
- Expanded Formula1 project by implementing tracking code and set up data filters using Google Analytics and Jquery. Explored new concepts through research using Google Cloud and NodeJS.

#### **Software Developer**

Motes & Bots Technologies

07/2018 - 02/2019

- Lead the team on the Smart Office Project to develop a secure and user-friendly website for office management, utilizing ReactJS, Firebase, NodeJS, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, and AWS.
- Features like user authentication and authorization was established, CRUD operations for employee data, and created modules for office management.
- Participated in the Smart Home application to create a safe and easy-to-use dashboard for home management, using the latest technologies like Angular, Firebase, NodeJS, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, and AWS.
- Gained knowledge of new technologies and implemented software development lifecycle, including the analysis, coding, building, testing, and deployment.

### **Software Engineer Intern**

Textron

07/2017 - 06/2018

Contributed on the Request Tracker website using C#, .NET Framework, HTML, CSS, and SQL Server. Collaborated with the team to design a dashboard for tracking requests, performing CRUD operations, creating a user-friendly interface, conducting testing, and fixing bugs.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Master of Science, Computer Science

01/2022 - 12/2023

California State University Los Angeles

GPA - 3.84/4

# Master of Technology, Computer Science & Information Security

08/2016 - 07/2018

Manipal Institute of Technology

**Bachelor of Science, Information Technology** 

06/2012 - 07/2016

Gujarat Technological University

#### RECENT PROJECTS

Data Visualization and Management Application (React, React Hooks, JSON, Highcharts, Material UI, Material React Table, exportto-csv, AOS, Firebase)

Integrated large and complex data into graphs and tables with features including filtering, sorting, downloading CSV files. pagination, and smooth animations.

Automated Restaurant Question-Answering app using ChatGPT API (React, Python, FastAPI, Langchain, OpenAI API, AWS, GIT, Github)

Defined a guery-based restaurant information retrieval app and established a backend system interfacing with the OpenAI API to extract details from restaurant menus. Improved the app's ability to understand and respond to user queries effectively.

## Personal Portfolio Website (ReactJS, Tailwind CSS, GIT)

 Designed and developed a personal website showing information that includes education, work experience, projects, skills, and contact details.

Task Management (VueJS, JSON, NodeJS, MongoDB, ExpressJS, HTML, CSS, Postman API)

• The dynamic and user-friendly task management application includes components such as users, employees, and projects, all uniquely linked and supporting CRUD operations.

### Security Algorithms (Java, C/C++)

· Generated security algorithms, such as RSA and DES.

## **SKILLS**

- Frontend: HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, React Hooks, Redux, Angular, Vue, ES6, Highchart, D3.js
- Backend: Nodejs, Java, Python
- Database: MongoDB, Firebase, SQL Server
- Cloud: AWS, Adobe Targets, Google Analytics, Google Tag Manager
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook, Microsoft Office, Google Collab, Eclipse, Postman, Wordpress, Photoshop, JIRA, GitHub
- Additional Skills: API, AJAX, JSON, Accessibility, Web Services, Software Development Life Cycle, Object-Oriented Programming, GIT, NPM, Gulp/Grunt, Bower, Handlebars, Nodemailer, Linux, Windows, Mac